

360.907.0107



gwhampton@gmail.com



Linkedin.com/in/ghampton



Bend, Oregon

Summary

Strategic digital marketing professional with experience in supporting an array of brands from Fortune 500 to startups. Aptitude for creative storytelling, leveraging digital properties for content distribution and building community.

Competencies

Integrated marketing campaigns

Garrett Hampton

Project management

Social & digital strategy

Content strategy

Community management

Facilitating training workshops

Experience

Crime & PartnersBend, OR

Digital Strategy | June 2016 - Present

Develop content, digital and social strategy for new business pursuits. Continuing freelance support on projects.



1859 MEDIA + Oregon Media Bend, OR

Digital Manager | July 2013 - May 2017

Developed the digital infrastructure for 1859 Media's publications: 1859 Oregon's Magazine, OnTrak Magazine, and Bend Magazine. Key functions included: managing social media strategy, facilitating website launches & redesigns, developing newsletter and digital app, reporting on 1859 digital properties.



- Digital strategy and execution for both 1859 Media properties and clients.
- Community growth: 1859 Magazine Social by 300%, Newsletter 175%, site traffic 35%.
- Integral in serving as liaison between Sales & Editorial for creating proposals and leveraging the editorial calendar to create relevant multi-platform campaigns.
- Recognized for our work and presented our achievements at the 2014 Oregon's Governor's Conference on Tourism.

NIKEPortland. OR

Global Associate Producer, Global Digital Brand | August 2011 - November 2012

Managed digital strategy for Nike Running & Nike Women. Key functions included: developing social media strategy, driving social media campaigns, analytics and measurement, content development, and developing influencer lists.



- Created an elite training experience for the Nike Running community: Nike Running Race Coach.
- Created content in partnership with Nike Elite Coaches and Athletes.
 - Resulted in 85,000+ downloads.
- Coordinated digital messaging, content publishing, and reporting of the Nike Running Community.
- Executed the vision of key brand moments (Product Launches, Nike Plus, Olympics).

Fit Right
Northwest
Running &
Walking
Portland, OR

Social Strategist + Event Coordinator | May 2010 - October 2011

 Managed and developed Fit Right Northwest's brand utilizing social media tools.



- Created excitement through social media around upcoming events, shoes/apparel, and health/fitness.
 - Resulted in increasing brand awareness and attendance to events/races + 43% follower growth rate.
- Coordinated FRNW presence at 60+ events.







ir

Linkedin.com/in/ghampton

360.907.0107

Mt. Hood Meadows Ski Resort Portland, OR

Communications Specialist | October 2009 - March 2010



- Promoted events, services and facilitated open communication with customers using social media channels and website.
- Developed partnerships with destination properties, created web content, assisted with group sales, and managed customer inquiries.

Hub World Travel LLC

Portland, OR

Operations Manager | January 2008 - September 2008



- Developed relationships with key partners, including: Oregon
 Convention Center, Travel Portland, Hotels, Wineries, Breweries, and other local attractions.
- Created tour routes, researched tour information, scheduled tours, and managed customer relations.

Tools

Social Media: Sprinklr, Nuvi, Hootsuite

Project Management: Basecamp, Asana, Opal

Software: Microsoft Office, Google Apps, Wordpress

Education

Bachelor of Arts

Sport Management | Business Administration Washington State University | Pullman, WA

Inbound Marketing Certificate

HubSpot Academy